Meghan Martin

UX/UI Designer

@ meghanxmartin@gmail.com

www.meghan.work

EDUCATION

M.A. Design Strategy

Instituto Europeo di Design

 Coursework: UX/UI Design, User Research, Visual Design, Design Thinking, Branding Strategy, Communication Strategy, Research Methods and Processes, Product Strategy, Social Impact and Sustainable Design

B.A. Political Economy

University of California at Berkeley

 Leadership: Design Director at Fashion and Student Trends, Creative Lead at BARE Magazine, International Project Coordinator at World Literacy Project, Giant Slalom competitor

EXPERIENCE

Founding UX/UI Designer

InnitData

m 08/2010 - Ongoing

 Collaborating with founders, design and development team to build UX/UI and implementation for early stage startup

UX/UI Designer (Contract)

Diversity Coalition

08/2020 - Ongoing

- Redesign of platform to promote and advocate for diversity and inclusion
- Leading design process through redesign of UX/UI and visual identity

UX/UI Designer (Contract)

Worldly

1 07/2020 - 09/2020

- Designed social media application for Gen Z to participate in activism
- Led startup through branding strategy, visual identity and UX/UI design

UX/UI Designer (Contract)

Covid Science Engine

1 05/2020 - 09/2020

- Designed an application for COVID-19 researchers that brings the time of digesting research to less than 30 seconds
- Created style guide and UI library and led front-end dev team to implementation in React
- Collaborated with larger team of two virologists, three front end developers, one backend developer and two machine learning data scientists

UX/UI Designer and Developer (Contract)

Los Arabis Vineyards

1 04/2020 - 06/2020

- Redesigned an outdated ecommerce website and implemented design with custom Shopify development
- Led project through the phases of discovery, style guides, branding process, prototypes, development and user testing

Product Designer and Strategic Consultant

IED Madrid

1 01/2019 - 12/2019

 UX/UI design and strategy for clients including ArcelorMittal, NH Hotel Group, 40+ location restaurant chain, international development organization, an email marketing SaaS product and an esports startup

SUMMARY

Driven and solution oriented UX/UI designer who loves to code and is passionate about crafting meaningful user experiences.

Experienced in web and mobile application design, front end programming and product strategy. I believe that doing is better than not doing, to always show up imperfectly, keep it simple and keep your ego out of it.

You can see more of my skillset and relevant design work at www.meghan.work.

CERTIFICATIONS

Interaction Design Specialization

University of California, San Diego

Full Stack Web Development:
Javascript, Ruby on Rails, HTML/CSS

Le Wagon

Visual Design and Branding, React.js, Animation for the Web, AJAX & APIs

SuperHi

PROJECTS

Fonts in the Wild

Designed and shipped <u>Fonts in the Wild</u>, a design resource to find free and paid font inspiration for commercial and personal projects

Fancier

During Le Wagon bootcamp, I led UX/UI design and on a team developed a social marketplace for preloved festival outfits; you can watch me pitch a demo of mobile-first Fancier live here

ACHIEVEMENTS



Featured Product Hunt Maker

<u>Launched product</u> currently at 2nd Product Hunt featured position for launch day at 480+ upvotes and 5/5 average reviews; Fonts in the Wild is used by thousands of users weekly



Team MVP

During Q1 of 2019, nominated MVP at Oracle due to new hire mentorship and highest quota attainment of an average of 228%